Sadie M. Fearen and A. Harry Chick Vaudeville Collection 1882-1933
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Sadie M. Fearen and A. Harry Chick Vaudeville Collection, 1883-1933
MS 489
Fearen, Sadie M.
Chick, A. Harry
Sadie M. Fearen Repertoire Company
Papers and photographs, 1889-1933, collected by the couple Sadie Fearen and Harry Chick vaudevillians from the Boston/New England area. Bulk of the collection includes theatre programs, cabinet card photographs of primarily east coast performers, White Rat Actors Union materials, newspaper clippings, and scrapbooks
2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Married couple Sadie M. Fearen and A. Harry Chick, were vaudeville performers and managers of the Sadie M. Fearen Repertoire Company in the New England area during the early 1900. As performers they were known for their singing, talking, and dancing comedy act. Sadie was also known as the “La Petite Sadie M. Fearen. As mangers of the Sadie M. Fearen Repertoire Company they would often preform and manage three act comedy plays such as Little Buckshot, Among the Breakers, and Triss, or Beyond the Rockies based on Western themes of mining and the 49ers. Some of the performers they managed for such plays include Fred Driscoll, Baby Irene Perry, and Richard H. Hogan. Touring the Boston and New England area they would play in theatres such as Bacon Hall in Somerville, MA as well as Natick, Woburn, and Winchester near the Boston area.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 4 series.
Series I: Printed Material, 1889-1933
Series II: Photographic Material, circa 1900s
Series III: Photographic Material, 1882-1917
Series III: Photographic Material, circa 1905-1920
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of vaudeville materials collected by vaudevillians Sadie M. Fearen and A. Harry Chick with the bulk of the materials compiled between 1905-1915. The printed materials include actor union materials such as White Rats Actor Union cards and the constitution of the Actor’s International Union. Printed materials also include contracts, theatre programs, plays, actor business cards, and correspondence. The bulk of the photographic materials include cabinet cards of male and female vaudeville performers such as Ella Collins, Frankie Bell, N.S. Wood, and Joseph Jefferson. Publications include the New York Clipper, the Player, and Popular Vaudeville. There are also two scrapbooks compiled by Fearen and Chick documenting many of the Sadie M. Fearen Repertoire Company performances.
Access Terms
Vaudeville
Blackface entertainers
Entertainers -- United States.
Theaters –- United States
White Rats of America
Container List
- Series I: Printed Material, 1889-1933
  This series is organized alphabetically and then by date. It contains Chick and Fearen documents as well as ephemeral materials relating to vaudeville.
  - Actors union, 1894-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address book, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Business cards – actors and businesses, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Business cards – Chick and Fearen, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Contracts, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1904-1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Plays, 1889-1903; undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Theatre Programs, 1892-1915; undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Theatre ticket stubs, circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vaudeville clippings, 1909-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Vaudeville fliers and ephemera, circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Photographs, circa 1900s
  This series is organized alphabetically and then by date. The series primarily contains cabinet cards of identified and unidentified actors.
  - Performance stills, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Performers, female – identified, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Performers, female – stereoviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Performers, female – unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Performers, groups – unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Performers, male – identified, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Performers, male – unidentified, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Richard “Dick” Riley and groups, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Theatre photographs, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Theatre postcards, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series III: Publications, 1882-1917
  Series organized alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - Burr McIntosh Monthly, 1903-1905 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - New York Clipper, May 20, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Salvation Army Song, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Player, 1913; 1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Popular Vaudeville, Noveber 1910 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Show Stop, February 1913 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Scrapbooks, circa 1905-1915
  This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically. The bulk of the two scrapbooks include theatre fliers and newspaper clippings from the Sadie M. Fearen Repertoire Company. Series includes titles of plays performed, actors, as well as theatre locations. The latter scrapbook primarily contains theatre booking contracts and ephemeral materials.
  - Theaters, circa 1905 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Theatres, circa 1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Vaudeville ephemera and booking contracts, circa 1910s (Box 4, Folder 1)